Ella Reeve Bloor Papers, 1890-1979
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS
  - Liberty Defense Union: printed material, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE - Friends and associates - Lochner, Louis]
  - Massachusetts Minimum Wage Commission: correspondence, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Mother Bloor Group, Lenin Division, National Training School: correspondence, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - National Civil Liberties Bureau: correspondence and printed material, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - National Miners Relief Committee: letterhead, circa 1927 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - National Party, Massachusetts headquarters: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - New York State Woman Suffrage Party: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - National Woman's Party: correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Omaha Defense Committee: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Pan American Labor Conference: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Pennsylvania Farmers Protective Association: correspondence, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - The People, editor: correspondence, circa 1896 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - People's Council for Democracy and Peace: printed material, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - People's Council of America: printed material, 1919, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Rand School of Social Science: correspondence and printed material, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - St. Louis Committee for the Maintenance of Constitutional Rights: printed material, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Socialist National Campaign and Defense Committee: business card, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Socialist Party
    - General: ballot, correspondence, printed material, receipt, 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Bronx County Organization: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Campaign and Organization Fund: correspondence and financial records, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Department of Organization and Propaganda: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - East Side Agitation Committee: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Hamilton, Ohio: correspondence, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Local Allegheny County: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - New York County: correspondence, 1917-18 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - New York State Committee: candidate list and correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Yonkers Local: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - United Cloth, Hat and Cap Makers Union and Millinery and Ladies Straw Hat Workers Union: ballot, letterhead, and publicity, 1913, 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - United Farmers League: publicity, undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - United Farmers Protective Association: printed material, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Unity Magazine: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Utica Lodge: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Walt Whitman Fellowship: postcards and publicity, 1917, undated (Box 10, Folder 64)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE - Friends and associates - Baines, Saunders, Sejsworth, Traubel]
  - Woman Suffrage Party of New York: questionnaire, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Women's International League: printed material, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Women's Non Partisan Committee: correspondence, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Workers Cooperative Association: membership card, undated (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Workers Defense Union: letterhead, membership cards, and printed material, 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Young Communist League (to Carl Reeve): correspondence, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 70)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES
  - Conscientious objectors: correspondence and printed material, 1917-19 (Box 11, Folder 1-1a)
  - Osteopathy: printed material, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Prohibition: printed material, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Songs: songbooks and sheet music, 1949, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union: booklet and Russian language newspapers, 1919, [see also Oversize materials] (Box 11)
  - Whitney, Anita: printed material, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Women: printed material, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified material, 1919, 1947, 1966, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS 1912-1947, .8 linear ft.
  The photographs in this series are arranged in three sections, Ella Reeve Bloor, Family, and Friends and associates.
  Especially noteworthy are the photographs of Bloor speaking to crowds and in association with other radical leaders such as Elizabeth Gurley Flynn and Paul Robeson.
  - Ella Reeve Bloor (originals)
    - Alone, 1917-1918 and 1941-49, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Speaking, 1925, 1939, 1942-43, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - At April Farm (booklet), undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - With identified others, 1940-42, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - With unidentified others, 1926-27, 1934, 1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Family and friends (original)
    - Olhomlt, Andrew, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Reeve family, 1940-44, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Ware family, circa 1920s-50, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Friends, acquaintances, and others (includes Elizabeth Gurley Flynn), 1912-48, undated (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous (includes slides), 1927-47, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies and printed pictures (not originals)
    - Alone, snapshots and portraits (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Speaking (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - At April Farm (booklet) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - With identified others (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - With unidentified others (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Family (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Friends, acquaintances, and others (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified (Box 13, Folder 15)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Soviet Union: booklet and Russian language newspapers 1919 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Portrait of Bloor by Stuyversant Van Veen 1946 (Map-case Flat File)
- MICROFILM, Microfilm (portions of collection) is located in Media Center (M46)